In today's video, I'm going to show you
how you can build a fully automated
trading bot from scratch using Cloud
Code. So, it will first detect the type
of market we're in, adjust your
portfolio allocations automatically, and
even places real trades for you. We're
not going to be building some basic
indicator bot that just buys when RSI
crosses above 30 like what you would
typically see on TradingView. Instead,
we're going to be building an actual
system that first connects to a real
brokerage so that you can automatically
place trades. Second, it'll manage your
risks with circuit breakers. And then
finally, it can even adapt to changing
market conditions automatically. And
we're going to be doing this without
writing any of the code ourselves. So,
if you've seen my previous videos, I go
over the concepts around using hidden
Markov models and walk-forward
backtesting engines. Today, we're going
to be taking those same concepts one
step further. So, we're going to grab
that same exact math, but now connect it
to a real broker so that we can have a
bot actually manage our portfolio for
us. So, make sure to stay until the end
of the video since I'll be covering how
to build this exact system step-by-step,
even if you have no technical knowledge
or you've never coded before. And just
as a disclaimer, I'm not a financial
advisor and this is not financial
advice. I'm not guaranteeing any profits
inside this video. All I'm doing is
showing you the concepts on how to build
a systemic trading framework to help you
become a more disciplined trader.
Trading involves real risk and it's up
to you to manage, validate, and
extensively test your own strategies.
So, here's what our automatic trading
bot dashboard looks like as a finished
product and what building by the end of
this video. So, up top we can first see
the detected regime, which is currently
neutral. This basically tells us how
volatile the market currently is and how
we should classify it. And then below,
we even have a confidence score. And
then to the right of this, we have our
portfolio value as well as our buying
power. Now again, this is connected
directly to a brokerage, in our case
Alpaca. So, these are the numbers that
are currently inside our trading
account. To the right of this, we have
the number of regimes that the current
system is categorizing the market into.
And right now the market's closed, so we
don't have any active positions. Then
below this, we just have simple price
actions with regime overlays. Below
this, we have volumes, confidence over
times, distributions. And this way
you'll be able to see how this actually
translates to your trading strategy. And
then below all of this, importantly, we
have the signal feed, which actually
shows all of the historical trades that
this automatic trading bot has placed.
So this way it'll tell you the
allocation from your portfolio size, as
well as entry prices, stops, and P&L in
real time. Then to the left of this, we
also have risk controls. And this
basically shows our circuit breakers,
drawdown limits, and leverage statuses,
so that we manage our risk properly and
obviously don't blow up our account.
Then finally, these are all of the
regimes that our trading system is
currently characterizing the market
into. So we have a crash, bear, neutral,
bull, and euphoria. And then obviously,
depending on the regime that the market
is currently in, our allocation is going
to change, and our strategies are going
to change as well. So the way you can
think about this is that depending on
the regime that our trading system is
currently detecting the market as, our
strategies are going to be different.
The amount of capital that we're going
to allocate per trade is going to be
different as well. And again, everything
here was built by Claude Code, right?
Which is a coding agent. All you'll need
to do is prompt properly, understand the
structure of your code base, and I'll be
going over this from start to finish, so
that you can have your own version of
this trading dashboard and automatic
trading bot for use yourself. Now,
before you start building out this
automatic trading bot, let me first
explain the system and all the things we
need to make step-by-step to ensure that
we have a comprehensive system that
covers everything we would theoretically
need. So you can think of this entire
system as being made up of five
components. We'll have the brain,
allocation, safety, brokerage, and then
finally the dashboard that displays all
of our information. So to start off,
right, every system needs a competent
brain at the center that basically makes
decisions. But, in our case, our brain
is going to be hidden Markov models.
Now, I've went over this in previous
videos, but you can think of this exact
system as essentially looking at the
market historically as well as with live
data and then classifying what type of
market we're in. So, by looking at
things like price action and volume,
it's able to classify the market. So,
it'll tell us if the market is in a
crash, if it's currently a bear market,
if it's in a bull market, or just
full-blown euphoria where everything
just goes up. And now, depending on the
type of market that we're in, the
strategies are going to differ, right?
So, inside our automatic trading bot, we
want to make sure this is as dynamic as
possible. And the way this bot is going
to trade inside a bear market or choppy
market is going to be very different
from a trending bull market. So, before
we ever make any trading decisions,
before we ever layer any strategies of
our own or yours on top, we need to know
first what type of market it is. So,
this is basically just how we should be
looking at the market before ever adding
any strategies. And that goes into my
next point, which is step two on
allocation. So, you can think of this
allocation layer as being directly
influenced by the brain. So, what this
means is that, depending on, you know,
the volatility regime, whether in a
crash, bear, neutral, bull, or euphoria,
it's going to change the amount we're
invested in our portfolio. So,
typically, in calm markets, you would
have a larger amount of capital
allocated. And then, in more turbulent
markets, you would typically reduce your
exposure to protect your capital. And
we're going to use those same exact
concepts inside our automatic trading
bot as well. Now, for our third
component, we have the safety net.
Essentially shuts everything down if
certain levels are hit. So, basically,
if you hit like a max drawdown in a day,
if your strategies aren't working like
they're supposed to, it's able to
essentially call it quits, uh shut off
the entire system. This way, you won't
continually lose money day by day, week
by week, or even during that same exact
day as well. Just depending on how you
structure these circuit breakers, which
I'll show you later on in the video. And
one thing to know is that these work
independently of our AI model. So,
whatever strategies, uh hidden Markov
models, systems we have, these safety
nets are going to be hardcoded in a
sense, so that even if our strategies
are technically built correctly, they
should work theoretically, these safety
nets are completely independent of that.
And this is huge, obviously, for
automated trading bots because you don't
ever want to just turn on a bot and have
it continually lose money, right? You'll
have to essentially call it quits at
some point and think about how to
revisit your strategy and how to
actually build a better system moving
forward. And then now for step four, we
have the broker. So, this is where you
can choose the brokerage that you want
to connect your system to. Two main
options I would typically consider. The
first is Alpaca. This is generally free,
depending on how much volume you're
trading. Obviously, if you get into like
millions of dollars of volume trading,
you're going to have fees on top of
this. Uh but once you do get to that
certain level, then I would probably
change to IBKR. This is going to be
paid. So, this is where our code can
place real orders directly through the
system to Alpaca. If you sign in to
Alpaca, which I'll show you later on in
the video as well, you'll be able to see
all your trades, performance, and how
much money you have in your account.
Then finally, to tie everything
together, we have the dashboard and this
is where you can see everything in real
time. So, now that we understand how
this automatic trading bot is going to
be structured, let's go ahead and build
out every single one of these components
one by one. So, this way you'll be able
to see like from step one till the end,
we're going to be following the same
exact timeline. Uh we're going to be
able to test independently. So, we're
going to be test that the HTML models
work. We're going to test that the
allocation and sizing works. We're going
to test that the safety net works as
well. We're going to test our strategies
and backtest those. We're going to be
testing our brokerage connection, so we
can first see that the trades are
actually getting placed through Alpaca.
And then finally, the dashboard will
essentially tie everything together.
Now, before we start building the
project, I basically inputted every
single step along the way inside this
master document. If you want to get
access to this, you can go ahead and
click the link in the description for my
school community. I'll go ahead and
showcase everything in a bit more detail
so that you can customize these to your
own strategies. I'll also show them in
the video, too. So, this way if you want
to just pause at certain parts of the
video to see how you would change up the
prompt, you can go ahead and do so. But,
just to give you a broad overview, what
we're first going to do is create the
project scaffolding. So, this is kind of
like the shell of the entire system.
Then, below this we have the regime
detection engine. So, this is going to
be the brain that we talked about. We
have the volatility-based allocation
strategies. These are where you're going
to input your custom strategies based on
how you trade and what you're actually
trading. Below this, we have
walk-forward backtesting and validation
to make sure that your strategy does
work properly. And then finally, we have
a risk management layer that ensures
that our system doesn't blow up our
account. We have proper, you know,
circuit breakers in place, things like
that. And then finally, once we've
validated that everything works and is
safe to a degree, we're able to connect
it to Alpaca, which is a brokerage we're
going to be using. Below this, we can
make sure that the main loop and
orchestration works. So, this is where
we're going to extensively test that
we're able to send trades to Alpaca.
It's receiving all our data. And then
finally, we're going to monitor, have
alerts, and have a dashboard that
showcases all of the trades we've taken,
historical performance, how our system's
currently working, and just a way to
visually see our system in real time.
Obviously, everyone trades very
differently, but the idea here is to
have a very a general base case that
almost anyone can use. Uh you just want
to go ahead and change the strategies,
change the tickers you're working with,
but obviously keep the core logic here
the same. Now that we've gone over the
structure, let's go ahead and start
building out this actual auto trading
bot project. So, the first thing you'll
need to do is go ahead and download an
IDE where you can use Cloud Code. This
is where your code base is going to
live, and in our case, we're going to be
using Visual Studio Code since it's
pretty much the simplest way to go go
and get started. So, all you'll need to
do is download Visual Studio Code and
then open up a blank folder inside your
computer. Next, what you want to do is
add Cloud Code as an extension. Search
Cloud Code. You should see it pop up as
the very first extension. It's called
Cloud Code for VS Code. This is the
easiest way to go ahead and get started.
So, now once you've installed the Cloud
Code extension, you should be able to
see it on this right-hand side here.
This is where we're going to be able to
chat with Cloud Code, which again is
going to help us make all the projects.
We're going to need to give it very
useful instructions one step at a time
based on the diagram I showed you
previously. Next, what we're going to be
doing is something called project
scaffolding. So, inside the section,
we're going to be creating just a
project structure. So, no actual logic
yet, but we're just going to be creating
a Python project called Regime Trader
with the following structure. And again,
there's nothing yet inside these files.
This structure is just what's going to
tell Cloud Code how our files are going
to look. First, we're going to have
settings, credentials, HMM engine. So,
this is going to be the brain. Then,
we're going to have regime strategies.
So, based on the regime that we're in,
it's going to have volume-based
allocation strategies. Then, we're going
to have a risk manager that's going to
handle position sizing, leverage,
drawdown limits. This is basically the
API wrapper that allows us to connect to
Alpaca, which is our brokerage. Then,
we're going to have an order executor.
This is what's going to allow us to
actually place trades to the Alpaca API.
So, as the name suggests, we're able to
place trades, modify trades, and even
cancel trades. We're also able to track
our open positions because once we're
connected to Alpaca, we can see
positions that are currently open. We
have market data, which is real-time and
historical. We have feature engineering,
which is technical indicators,
structured logging, the dashboard. This
is where our dashboard's going to live.
Alerts, so email, webhook alerts for
critical events. This is if you ever
want to connect your email. Below this,
we have the backtester. We have
performance. So, here we're able to
calculate the sharp ratios, drawdowns,
regime breakdowns, benchmarks. This is
everything you saw inside the main
dashboard that I showcased initially, uh
which basically gives us our strategy as
a whole, how it relates to the overall
market. Then below those, we have all of
the tests that we're going to be
running. This is the verify like no look
ahead biases, testing out strategies,
risks, order, etc. And we're going to be
doing extensive testing each step of the
way because again, this is going to be
an automated trading bot and we have to
make sure that it's being validated at
every step. And then finally, we just
have the main file, requirements, and
then the ENV file is where we're going
to be storing our credentials. If we're
going to be using the Alpaca API, this
is where we're going to store the API
keys that allow us to connect to our
live account. Below this, we need a
requirements file that basically has
everything we're going to be using
inside this trading framework. Then
finally, we want to create a settings
file that has all the parameters. Now,
this is where you're essentially going
to be changing the tickers that you want
to focus on. Then below this, we have
more specific parameters for the hidden
Markov models, the strategies that we're
going to be using depending on the
regimes, risks, back tests, and
monitoring. Again, we don't want to
implement any logic yet. So now, let's
go ahead and run this. So after waiting
like 5 minutes or so, we can see the
project skeleton is complete. We have 31
files across eight directories. The
first is going to have settings with all
the parameters. So this is the broker
we're going to use, the HMMs,
strategies, risks, back tests, and
monitoring. Next, we have the core. So
these are the core parameters that we're
going to be using inside the framework,
where we're getting data from,
monitoring, back testing. And if we go
over here to the left, we can even see
all of these files are created inside
regime trader. And again, this is pretty
much standardized no matter what
strategy you have. Cloud code does work
best when it has the structure all built
out before we start diving deep into the
weeds. Now that we finished project
scaffolding, the next step is to create
the brain of our entire trading bot. So
again, like I mentioned, these aren't
going to predict prices. They're going
to predict the type of environment that
the current market is in, whether it's
calm, volatile, whether we're in a bear
market. So, by detecting these different
types of environments, we're able to
reduce our exposure, change our
strategies. So, in this next prompt, we
can see that we're going to be
implementing the HMMs, and this is going
to be a volatility classifier. It's
going to tell us the type of
environment, like I mentioned. Below
this, we want to do different types of
tests to see how many regimes there are.
So, inside my example from the beginning
of the video, you saw that we had five
regimes, right? But, the five wasn't
hardcoded. That's actually something we
found out through testing. So, the idea
here is that this model is going to
test, you know, three through seven
regimes, and then this is automatically
going to pick the best number of
regimes. So, instead of us guessing how
many there should be, we're just going
to have this math here dictate that.
Then, below this, we're just going to
sort the regimes by mean return. This is
going to help us label the regimes. So,
with three, it's only bear, neutral,
bull. With four, it's crash, bear, bull,
euphoria. Five would be crash, bear,
neutral, bull, euphoria. Then, below
this, we have a bunch of functions that,
again, you can copy and paste or just
get it directly from my community. But,
you can pause and see any of the very
specific calculations we're going to be
running inside these functions. And
then, below this, this is how we're
going to actually train the HMMs with
around two years of daily data. Below
this is the regime detection. Now, one
important thing to know, especially if
you want to run this yourself, is that
the default predict function inside the
HMM library is processes the entire
sequence of data, but that generally
creates look-ahead bias. So, what we do
is make a slight tweak here to not use
the model predict function. Instead,
what we're going to be using is the
forward algorithm only. So, make sure to
include this inside your prompt, and
this is just to ensure that there's no
look-ahead bias when you're developing
these models and strategies. So, here
you can see the function. If I slowly
scroll down, you can see the mandatory
tests. And then, below this, we have the
regime stability filter, as well as
additional methods for predicting,
getting regimes, detecting regimes, and
then finally, how we classify the
states, and then log regime changes as a
warning. This is just for our
information. And then with the way we
build this out here, Quad has a
stability filter inside this engine.
What this means is that a certain regime
has to persist for at least three
consecutive bars before the system acts
on it. So if it's like flickering
between bull, bear, bull, bear, it's not
actually going to do anything if it
flickers more than four times in the
past 20 bars. That is what causes
uncertainty. So we're going to log those
changes as kind of like a warning sign.
So this way it does reduce your position
sizes ultimately because it is more
volatile and uncertain as to what regime
the market is currently in. All we're
building here is again just the brain,
right? That detects the type of market
before you apply any other allocation
strategies. So here after like 10
minutes or so, since we had such a
robust prompt, it basically implemented
everything we asked for inside these two
files, so the feature engineering as
well as the HMM engine, which is again
going to be the main brain. It's also
passing and validating the test that we
had it complete after completing these
sections to ensure that first of all the
HMMs fit the validations, uh they're
doing predictions correctly, and then
there's no look-ahead bias as well.
Next, what we're going to want to do is
our allocation strategies, and this is
how the bot is going to tell us how to
size positions based on the regime that
we're in. Here we can see that the HMMs
excel at detecting volatile
environments, and then based on the
environments, we would essentially have
fully invested portfolios, stay invested
if the trend's intact, or just reduce
your allocations completely. So below we
have a fairly simple strategy that
obviously you would want to change if
you're going to customize this to your
own framework. But what I have here is
three main distinctions. The first is
that when volatility is low, to be fully
invested at 95% of your portfolio with
1.25x leverage. And then when the
volatility's medium, we can stay
invested if the trend is intact. But
again, this is the part that you're
going to customize. So maybe you would
want to be more aggressive in a low
volume market. Maybe you'd want to have
a different filter for medium volumes.
And then obviously you'd want to add
your own specific strategies on top as
well. So the idea here is that you just
want to replace this entire section with
your own personal strategies depending
on your own risk tolerances. And then
below this we have the volatility rank
mapping strategy orchestrator. We have
confidence and uncertainty. So again, a
lot of these are hardcoded based on what
I found works. There's also rebalancing.
This is how we're going to implement
everything. So we have a base case, we
have the low volume bull strategy,
strategy orchestrator, signal data
class. And then below this we just have
some aliases and labels. This is going
to be the part where you spend the most
amount of time in. And before we even
connect to a brokerage, we want to prove
and make sure that our strategy does
work. So the idea is to tweak this a
bit. What we're going to do is first
send over this prompt just to have our
base strategies layered in. And then
once we add in backtesting, we can go
back and forth with Claude Code to
really optimize a strategy that works
for your specific use case and your
asset class or ticker that you're
trading. And also we can see that all 32
tests pass. Again, we want to make sure
that we have tests on every single phase
of our build out. Below this we can see
our different strategies, which again is
a very general strategy that you would
obviously change based on how you trade
and based on what tickers you're trading
as well. We just have different
strategies on the type of regime. Below
this we have the key components. Next,
what we're going to want to do is build
out the walk forward backtesting engine.
And this is what's going to allow us to
test out that strategy we just
implemented to see if it works on blind
data historically and also how it's
potentially going to do in the future.
So what we're going to be doing here is
splitting data into rolling windows. And
this allows us to do an allocation based
walk forward backtest. This isn't like a
traditional backtest because typically
you would have all the data, find the
perfect settings in hindsight, and then
have it pretend that it predicted the
future. With this we're able to run
blind test historically to see how it
would have actually done without having
all the data beforehand. And I'm just
expanding out this prompt just so you
can read it a bit more clearly. If you
want to pause in certain parts of the
video, you can and take in some of these
concepts and then basically tailor it to
whatever strategy you're running. But
the logic should remain largely the
same. So the idea is that we want to
build out this walk-forward optimization
engine. So we'll have rolling windows
and the in-sample windows will be 252
trading days.
Out of sample will be around 6 months
for evaluations. So you can see how
we're running this allocation-based
backtest. Below this we have the math as
well as realistic simulations. This is
just for slippage. And then finally we
have performance metrics. So we want to
calculate the total return, the sharp
ratio, max drawdowns, win rates, total
trades, things like that just be able to
quantify how it actually performed. Then
we'll want to make sure that this is
separated out by regime as well as
confidence bucketed so we know if it's
high confidence trades that are
outperforming low confidence trades and
vice versa. Then we're going to want to
compare the backtest to three main
benchmarks. The first is buy and hold.
Obviously, if you were to take a ticker,
you would see how our strategy performed
simply by actively trading it versus
just buying and holding for that entire
historical window. We would also want to
compare against the 200-day SMA trend
following. This is one of the most
common systemic strategies and then
below this we just have a random entry
and random allocation changes with same
risk rules. And then if you want to go
even more in-depth, we have stress tests
that just basically inject random crash
events. So this is just to bake in very
specific like 10 to 15% in a day drops.
So on this step, obviously you're going
to need to go back and forth with your
own strategy. Make sure that you're
backtesting it properly. This is
honestly going to take the longest
amount of time at least for you because
once you do have a strategy dialed in,
you're probably going to need a lot of
iterations before you find something
that really does pass all these stress
tests as well as the benchmark
comparisons. After you go back and forth
with Quad Code, you should end up with
first a backtester file that will show
all of the windows that it's currently
testing your strategy on as well as the
other components. And then below this,
you should have a performance file that
shows all the metrics. So, your core
metrics, trade stats, regime tables,
confidence buckets, things of that sort.
So, you can see how your strategy
performed. And obviously, you would want
to go back to the drawing board, change
up your strategy, things of that sort if
your performance hasn't been too stellar
historically, at least. And then below
this, we should have stress test. This
just shows how your performance handled
under extreme stress in the market. And
all of this information should be tested
and should pass based on our prompt.
Now, after we verify and validate the
backtesting results, what we need to do
is build a layer that guarantees in the
worst case of trading, it's going to
stop our system. And this is what I
talked about earlier, which is the risk
management layer. This is probably the
most important system in your entire
trading framework, more important than
the HMMs, even. Because a mediocre
strategy with a great risk management
layer only loses money a little bit. If
you had a great strategy, but with bad
risk management, you could basically
blow up your account. So, basically, you
can think of this risk management as
having the absolute veto power over
everything. We'll have circuit breakers
basically built in here. So, if it's
down 2% in a single day, all sizes are
cut in half. If it's down over 3%, close
everything. If it's down 5% in a week,
then you want to half your sizes. If
it's down 10% from peak, so you have a
10% drawdown, the bot just stops
completely and writes a block file that
you have to manually delete. These are
here just to make sure that you don't
blow up your account, right? You can
have a great strategy, but a few bad
days can basically trigger some of
these. And if you don't have these in
place, things can spiral out of control
fairly quickly. And this last one here
that I have highlighted is pretty
deliberate. If it's down 10%, if you see
how it's going to write this file, what
that means is that you have to go look
at what happened. It's going to go ahead
and write a file for you, so you
understand what went wrong in the
strategy if it was really down 10% from
peak. Uh you go inside, you understand
why this occurred, and then you have to
consciously and manually turn it back
on. So, this forces you to go into the
system, see what happened, and you need
to manually delete this file to resume
your strategy. And this is just to make
sure that you trust the strategy moving
forward because this can be a pretty
significant blow in your account. Now,
below this we have position level risk.
This is basically sizing. So, every
trade risks a maximum 1% of your
portfolio. Now, you can obviously change
this if you want a bit more risky. Then
below this, we have leverage, which
again you would want to change to your
own tolerances, what you're comfortable
with. Then below this, we have order
validation and then correlation checks.
So, before opening a new position, the
bot checks if it's correlated with any
existing positions. This is just a way
to make sure that we're not entering the
same type of trades. But the idea here
is that I want to give you the core
logic that should be able to be applied
generally, no matter what kind of trader
you are, but obviously change some of
these settings if you want to. So, here
you can see that the risk manager has
been built with all the thresholds. You
can see the circuit breakers and all of
their trigger levels. And then below
this, we have, you know, the minimum
size, risk-based sizing, position
limits, things of that sort. So,
everything we talked about. You can go
ahead into the file if you want to
validate, but we have test again on
every single step to make sure that
everything is passing. So, now if you
were to look at the timeline of our
automatic trading bot, we've built out
the brain that's going to classify the
market. Uh this is everything that
drives decisions. We've built out the
allocation and strategies. These are how
much of the portfolio to invest in and
how to invest. And we just finished out
the safety as well. So, this way we have
circuit breakers in case losses hit a
certain level. So, with this, we
basically have the core engine done.
What we next need to do is connect this
to a brokerage, and in our case Alpaca.
And then with the brokerage, we're able
to send trades directly from the system
here to the broker. The broker can
automatically place trades for you
without you lifting a finger, hence
making it fully automatic. So now, let's
go ahead and sell back and I'll show you
how to create your free account and
connect everything inside Cloud Code. So
what you'll first want to do is head
over to alpaca.markets
and this is the API for stocks, options,
and crypto trading. This way you'll be
able to automatically place trades from
our system for all these asset classes,
just not futures. Go ahead and click
sign up and what you want to use is the
trading API. Now once you've created
your account, it'll automatically place
you in a paper trading account. Now what
I would recommend is to start with this
trading account first, connect your
system to it, monitor it for at least a
month to make sure that everything is
working and that your strategy does seem
to potentially have an edge. And only
once you've done extensive testing and
even live market testing, would I then
click open live account on that same
strategy. Again, make sure that the
trades are being sent properly, but we
can do this in a paper account. This way
we can validate that our strategy works
in the meantime, make sure that trades
are being sent and then because it's a
paper trading account, we can do as much
testing as you want back and forth to
really hone in our strategies. So inside
your account, what you'll want to do is
scroll all the way down and you should
have a section called API keys. It'll go
ahead and give you a secret key as well
as your API key. So all you need to do
is copy these three things. The first is
this endpoint, this will be your base
URL. Then copy this, this will be your
API key and then copy this, this will be
your secret key. So these are the three
things that'll let you connect from
Cloud Code's trading system that it's
building for you directly to your actual
account here at Alpaca. And then
obviously, this goes without saying,
never share these keys with anybody. I'm
going to regenerate these after this
video as well. This is just to make sure
that no one has access to your funds,
especially if it's a live account. This
is something that we're not going to
have Cloud do for us and the reason for
that is because we don't want to share
sensitive information like API keys
directly to their chat. This is
something we're going to have to do
ourselves and it'll be super simple.
We've already built out the core
structure, so nothing much to do. So if
you go over to get ignore, you can see
that the .env files are going to be
ignored. This means that if you publish
this, your .env files won't ever be
leaked. They're going to be private. And
you can even see an example of what this
looks like. So, Claude code from our
very first prompt has already created
the structure for us. Alpaca API key,
this is just that API key I told you to
copy. Secret key is that secret key I
told you to copy. And then paper, this
can be true. You'll also need the base
URL as well, but since that's not
confidential, we can just type it into
the chat here. What's important is that
we never share the API key or the secret
key to Claude code. We want to just type
this in ourselves. So, all you want to
do is very simple. Go ahead and create a
new file, and then this will be our .env
file. Uh paste it here, and then what
you want to do is fill in your API key,
fill in your secret key, and then keep
this to be true. So, after that, I can
show you the prompt now for the Alpaca
broker integration. What we first want
to do is create this file that's going
to allow us to connect. We already have
the base URL here, so this is the URL
that you copied from that very first
step inside Alpaca. It's going to be
pretty much the same. What you'll see
here is that our credentials are in our
.env files. So, again, never hardcoded.
Then below this, we have all the other
parameters. Broker order executor, this
just lets us actually submit orders,
cancel orders, modify stops, things like
that. We also have a position tracker,
so we're able to see all the orders that
we currently have, as well as market
data. Now, this prompt isn't going to be
something custom like those allocation
strategies. It's pretty much going to be
the same for everyone. So, if you want
to take a screenshot of this section of
the video, feel free to do so. So, now
after we paste this in, it's able to
read our .env files and then help
connect us to the Alpaca API directly.
Now, after we submitted everything, we
just want to do a quick check to make
sure that the API is connected. Confirm
API is connected. The base URL, again,
is that base URL we copied with the
secret and the API keys. And then what
we want to do is place a trade for
Nvidia as a test, and we should see this
trade come through to our Alpaca
dashboard as well. So, go Go and click
enter here. And we can even see here as
it's loading, the API is connected, the
account is active with around 100,000 in
paper equity. Market's currently closed
cuz it's the weekend, but with paper
trading you can still have orders queue.
So, if they're going to place a test buy
for Nvidia, we should be able to see it
inside our Alpaca dashboard. And over
here on the Alpaca dashboard, again,
this is our paper account. If we scroll
down, we can see asset was Nvidia. It
was just a market buy. Uh we can even
see the date was literally right now, so
it was submitted on April 4th at 4:47.
So, this basically confirms to us that
the system is basically connected to our
Alpaca brokerage here. Now that we have
all the components of our system built
out with the brain, HMMs, we have the
strategies, allocations, we also have
the actual brokerage connected as well
as safety, back test, things of that
sort. We just want to connect everything
together with phase seven here. So,
basically, when we start up the system,
we want to load the configuration,
connect to Alpaca, verify the account,
check market hours to see if it's open
or closed, train the HMMs. We would then
want to initialize risk manager,
initialize position tracker, start all
the data feeds, things of that sort. So,
this is basically the bridge that ties
everything we've built thus far. And
then below this, we have the main loop
for each bar close. Default is 5-minute
bars. Then below this, we have shutdowns
in case that needs to be used, error
handling just to ensure that if there's
any issues with the Alpaca API, if the
server is down on their end, or if
there's any HMM errors on our end, uh
data feed drops, things of that sort.
This is just sure that our engine keeps
running smoothly no matter what happens
either on our end or their end. So, now
let's go ahead and copy and paste this
into Cloud Code, and this will
essentially glue everything. And while
we wait for this to run, basically, uh
this is the last step before we create
the dashboard to visually show
everything, but technically, once this
is wired, we don't really need a
dashboard. That's only if you want to
visually see what's happening in your
system, which I highly recommend. But,
if you don't, you can stop at this step
and just continually test out your
strategies, uh watch the orders go in on
the Alpaca dashboard. Awesome. Now, here
we can see that all 134 tests pass,
basically every single test that
connects every component of our trading
system. And as a final step, all we need
to do is make this a bit more visual so
we can see everything that's happening
from the back end onto our UI and make
any changes as necessary. So, this is
what the monitoring alerts and dashboard
prompt looks like. We just want to make
sure that all of our trades are being
monitored and logged properly. Uh we're
going to use this monitoring for
different positions, uh recent signals.
So, after pasting in that prompt, if you
wanted a visual dashboard, you can just
say build a Streamlit dashboard as the
UI. So, after a while, we can see that
all 134 tests pass. All our monitoring
and logging works for the trades. And
then as a final step, we just asked it
to install the dependencies needed to
run the Streamlit dashboard. And
awesome, let's go ahead and paste this
into our browser. Now, here we can see
our final dashboard. So, obviously, it's
still on a paper account. We have our
portfolio values. Right now, the
market's closed, so it's not going to
show any positions active. But, the idea
here is to always, you know, test
rigorously. Make sure this works on a
paper account, whichever strategy you're
running. You can see all the trades
coming in, whether they're performing or
not. Below this, we have the regime
detection. So, this is what tells us the
volatility of the market. Right now,
it's saying we're in a bear regime with
100% confidence. We also have risk
statuses in case we ever use any
leverage or if we're hitting any circuit
breakers. Below this, we also have
portfolios. So, obviously, right now, we
just created the system, so there's no
open positions. But, the idea is to
constantly monitor this dashboard day in
and day out as the system finds more
trades for you, logs them based on your
strategy, and you're able to see the
performance. So, that's the entire
system. A few important things to note.
First is to obviously paper trade for at
least a month. You want to make sure to
watch every decision your bot's making
for you, understand why it rebalanced
your portfolio, why it stayed put, when
the risk manager overruled something.
Again, recall back all those different
rules we had set. Next, the allocation
numbers here are swappable, and so you
can always change up your strategy, how
much of your portfolio is going to be
allocated in certain regimes. These can
always change depending on testing. It's
basically paper trade, review every
single rebalance, run back test across
different tickers, periods, iterate on
your allocation parameters, on your
strategies, and then use Cloud Code to
continually improve. So, the beauty of
this system is that it actually created
documentation for every single file we
built. So, if you were to hop into VS
Code, if you go over to the read me
file, you can see an overview of the
entire system. So, with this entire
system, Cloud Code basically knows your
code base in and out. If you ever need
to make any changes, it's able to add
them on the fly. Um it's able to review
its work. So, this is going to take a
lot of back and forth, but the
potentials here are basically limitless.
And like I mentioned earlier in the
video, if you want more detailed guides
and the complete prompt here, you can
click the link in the description for my
community. I also have custom one-to-one
projects if you want to build out a
custom strategy or system that you're
using. And if you found this video
helpful, make sure to like, comment, and
hit subscribe as I go over everything
regarding using AI for trading. I think
tools like Cloud Code have really opened
up the possibility for retail traders to
really quantify the strategies. They're
able to use systems like these that were
previously never really accessible to
the average Joe, but now almost anyone
can hop into Cloud Code, build out these
super complex systems, test out their
strategies, and just help them become a
more disciplined and profitable trader.